William Thomas Rawleigh Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
William Thomas Rawleigh Papers 1911-1931
MSS59584
Rawleigh, William Thomas, 1870-1951
1,500 items
9 containers
4.3 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Manufacturer and retailer of farm goods, chairman of the La Follette for President Committee, and Robert M. La Follette's campaign treasurer. Correspondence, financial records, lists, charts, promotional material, and others papers relating to the 1924 presidential campaign of Robert M. La Follette (1855-1925).
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Brunson, Hartwell L.--Correspondence.; Ekern, Herman Lewis, 1872-1954--Correspondence.; Holmes, Fred L., 1883-1946--Correspondence.; Johnston, William Hugh, 1874-1937--Correspondence.; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1855-1925.; MacGowan, Charles J.--Correspondence.; Nelson, John Mandt, 1870-1955--Correspondence.; Rawleigh, William Thomas, 1870-1951.; Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1949--Correspondence.
Organizations
Progressive Republican League of Illinois.; W.T. Rawleigh Company.
Subjects
Presidents--United States--Election--1924.; Progressivism (United States politics)
Places
United States--Politics and government--1901-1953.
Occupations
Campaign managers.; Manufacturers.; Merchants.
Provenance
The papers of William Thomas Rawleigh, manufacturer and retailer of farm goods, chairman of the La Follette for President Committee and treasurer of the National Joint La Follette-Wheeler Committee, were received by exchange from DePaul University Library, Chicago, Illinois, in 1980.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of William Thomas Rawleigh are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1870, Dec. 3 Born near Mineral Point, Wis.
1889 Retailer of household goods, veterinarian remedies, and poultry supplies
1890 Married Minnie B. Trevillian
1895 Established the W. T. Rawleigh Co. (president, 1906-1907)
1906 1907 Member, City Council, Freeport, Ill.
1909 Purchaser and editor, Freeport Daily Standard, Freeport, Ill.
1909 1911 Mayor, Freeport, Ill. Vice president, Illinois Mayors Association
1910 1912 Representative, Illinois House of Representatives
1911 Chairman, Freeport-Hughes Alliance (president, 1916) Presidential elector, Progressive Party
1911 1912 Expanded the W. T. Rawleigh Co. with branches in Memphis, Tenn., and Winnipeg, Canada, and offices and warehouses in Mexico, France, Zanzibar, and Madagascar, and plantations in the Comeres Islands
1911 1917 President, Rawleigh-Schryer Co.
1923 Married M. Marguerite Schneider
1924 Chairman, La Follette for President Committee Treasurer, National Joint La Follette-Wheeler Committee
1951 Died
Scope and Content Note
The papers of William Thomas Rawleigh (1870-1951) span the years 1911-1931 and consist primarily of material relating to the 1924 presidential campaign of Robert M. La Follette (1855-1925). Included is correspondence, financial records, lists, charts, promotional material, printed matter, and miscellaneous material. Also in the collection is correspondence concerning the Progressive Republican League of Illinois and material related to the W.T. Rawleigh Company, which Rawleigh established. Correspondents include Hartwell L. Brunson, Herman Lewis Ekern, Fred L. Holmes, Willliam Hugh Johnston, Charles J. MacGowan, John Mandt Nelson, and Oswald Garrison Villard.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is organized by type of material.
Container List
- Robert M. La Follette (1855-1925), campaign material (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - 1924 (Box 1)
      - Mar. 29-Aug. 31, (7 folders) (Box 1)
      - Sept. 1-26, (5 folders) (Box 2)
      - 3 Sept. 27-Oct. 12, (4 folders) (Box 3)
      - Oct. 13-31, (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1924, Nov. 1-1925, Jan. 10, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Accounts and funds (Box 5)
    - Bank statements and cancelled checks (Box 5)
    - Contribution cards, (2 folders); (3 folders); (5 folders) (Box 5, Box 6, Box 7)
    - Expenses (Box 7)
    - Miscellany (Box 8)
    - Receipt stubs, (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Treasurer’s reports (Box 8)
  - Biographical file (Box 8)
  - Miscellany (Box 8)
  - Notes (Box 8)
  - Petition lists (Box 8)
  - “Platforms and Performances/A Comparison,” chart (Box 8)
  - Printed matter (Box 8)
  - Progressive Democrats and Republicans, lists, 1923-1924 (Box 8)
  - Shipping orders (Box 8)
- La Follette’s Magazine (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1921, Aug. 26-1926, June 22 (Box 9)
  - Miscellany (Box 9)
  - Printed matter (Box 9)
  - Promotional material, drafts (Box 9)
- Progressive Republican League of Illinois, correspondence (Box 9)
  - 1911, Aug. 9-1912, Feb. 2 (Box 9)
- W. T. Rawleigh Company, printed matter (Box 9)
- Printed matter (Box 9)
  - General (Box 9)
  - Clippings, (4 folders) (Box 9)